Guide to the Charles E. Bigelow and Bay State Shoe Factory Papers circa 1840-1939 MS 3110
New-York Historical Society
Charles E. Bigelow and Bay State Shoe Factory papers
circa 1840-1939
New-York Historical Society
MS 3110
19 Linear feet in 14 cartons and 10 document boxes
Personal papers of Charles Bigelow, including family correspondence, photographs, and househould records; as well as business papers for the Bay State Shoe Factory. Includes financial records, factory reports, business correspondence, and legal documents.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Arrangement
TBD
Biographical / Historical
TBD
Immediate Source of Acquisition
TBD
Related Materials
TBD
Scope and Contents
TBD
- Bigelow family papers, 1840-1883, 1900s (Box 1)
- Bigelow family photos & cards, 1900s (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Maps, brochures, pamphlets, travel brochures, shoe nails display case.
- Miscellaneous bills & receipts (Box 1 of 2), 1890s-1930s (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous bills & receipts (Box 2 of 2), 1890s-1930s (Box 4)
- Bay State Shoe Factory records, 1870s-1890s (Box 5)
  Leather samples, canvas samples, correspondence, printed materials
- Bay State Shoe factory records, 1870s-1890s (Box 6)
- Yale-related ephemera, 1869-1873 (Box 7)
  Printed materials, ephemera, correspondence, etc.
- Business correspondence, circa 1896-1900 (Box 8)
- Household account books; Invitations, calling cards, 1850s-1930s (Box 9)
  Household account books (1850s-1930s); calling cards and invitations (1870s-1920s)
- Beaconlamp Raritan Electric Manufacturing Co. papers, circa 1898-1905 (Box 10)
  Business correspondence, financial records
- Bigelow family letters, 1870s-1930s (Box 11)
- Commonwealth Shoe & Leather: Boston; Related to Bay State Papers, Old Colony Boot & Shoe (Box 1 of 2), circa 1895-1910 (Box 12)
  Business correspondence, financal documents, legal documents, factory reports (postcards)
- Commonwealth Shoe & Leather: Boston; Related to Bay State Papers, Old Colony Boot & Shoe (Box 2 of 2), circa 1895-1910 (Box 13)
- Lyall & Reinsburg papers; Art collection; Business; Biographical, 1870s-1930s (Box 14)
  Legal Documents, Financial documents, Business correspondence, correspondence, documents (German)
- Bay State Shoe & Leather Co. papers (Box 1 of 7), circa 1880-1920 (Box 15)
  Pamphlets, samples from shoe factory (including government reports on prison manufacturing), financial documents, business correspondence.
- Bay State Shoe & Leather Co. papers (Box 2 of 7), circa 1880-1920 (Box 16)
- Bay State Shoe & Leather Co. papers (Box 3 of 7), circa 1880-1920 (Box 17)
- Bay State Shoe & Leather Co. papers (Box 4 of 7), circa 1880-1920 (Box 18)
- Bay State Shoe & Leather Co. papers (Box 5 of 7), circa 1880-1920 (Box 19)
- Bay State Shoe & Leather Co. papers (Box 6 of 7), circa 1880-1920 (Box 20)
- Bay State Shoe & Leather Co. papers (Box 7 of 7), circa 1880-1920 (Box 21)
- Bigelows in Brooklyn; Charles Bigelow personal correspondence, bills, receipts, deeds (Box 1 of 3), circa 1870-1900 (Box 22)
- Bigelows in Brooklyn; Charles Bigelow personal correspondence, bills, receipts, deeds (Box 2 of 3), circa 1870-1900 (Box 23)
- Bigelows in Brooklyn; Charles Bigelow personal correspondence, bills, receipts, deeds (Box 3 of 3), circa 1870-1900 (Box 24)